VASILEIOS FOTOPOULOS

PERSONAL ELEMENTS

First Name: Vasileios Last Name: Fotopoulos

Nationality: Hellenic (EU Citizen – no work restriction)

CONTACT INFORMATION

Address: Hradešínská 66, Prague 101 00 Mobile Phone: +42 0775455116

Skype ID: bill.delk

E-mail: vasilhsfoto@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Senior back-end engineer with records building systems for various industries. Experienced with Java EE technology stack and Spring ecosystem. Solid understanding of OOP, Design Software Patterns, Data Base Design. Exposed to Big Data technologies (Couchbase, Elastic search, Oracle NoSQL, Hadoop).

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

December 2018 – December 2019 Omio (formerly GoEuro) Prague, C.R

Description Fast Integration product. On boarding bus agencies, taking routes/trips/fares data and enabling them to sell their tickets via the Omio web site.

Role Senior Software Engineer.

Micro service architecture deployed in Kubernetes.

Technologies Node.js v10 services with express 4, ajv 6 for validation, testing with mocha, sinon, chai, nock.

Java services in Java SE 11 with Maven, written in Spring Boot 2, spring-boot-starter-web, spring-boot-starter-actuator, spring-data-couchbase, Lombok, Mapstruct. UT and Integration testing using: Junit5,

Mockito, assertJ, mockMvc.

Data storages: Couchbase CE 6, Google data store.

Metrics: Dropwizard via Micrometer to report metrics in graphite/Logs: ELK infrastructure.

Responsibilities

- Being a key member in the team to transform a POC application to a product.
- Designing/setting up/implementing CRUD restful APIs in node JS to store agency data into CB for automating the on-boarding process of new agencies.
- JS scripts to read GTFS data from Google spreadsheet to insert fares/ticket codes via restful API into CB to enable price editing for our agencies via UI.
- Setting up repository using Spring to implement CRUD restful APIs for storing routes/trips/stops data into CB for enabling our agencies to edit their data from UI.

January 2016 – September 2018 Oracle Prague, C.R

Description Internet of Things (IoT).

Role Principal Member of Technical Staff.

Technologies Java EE 7 (JAX-RS, CDI, Bean Validation, JPA), Swagger API, WebLogic 12c, Coherence, Elastic Search,

Oracle NoSQL, Oracle DBAAS, Gradle, Testng/Mockito.

Responsibilities

- First 5 months as part of INFRA team; developed a rest API, part of the provisioning flow, for executing scripts for onboarding IoT analytics part into production.
- Being a key member for designing and building <u>Connected Worker (CW)</u> application atop of IOT platform:
 - o Employee registration service to embedded WL LDAP.
 - o Being part of a team who migrated user registration logic to Oracle Identity Cloud Service for all of our applications in the IoT ecosystem.
 - o Project assignment service.
 - Enabling KPI's calculation into CW. Recording historical values for workers into Elastic Search and Oracle NoSQL.

July 2013 - December 2015

Barclays Capital Investment Bank

Prague, C.R

Description

Pre-settlement team. Processing settlements from different streams (cd, fx, ird) applying business rules for dealing with validations, updates, netting while sending payments to be executed by a central system.

Technologies

Java SE 6, Spring framework (DI, AOP), Hibernate, MSSQL server, Maven, Spring MVC, MyBatis, JSP, Apache Tiles, CSS for UI, Apache Tomcat 6.

Responsibilities

- Analysis, design, implementation and end-to-end testing using an internal in-house framework.
 Full ownership of specific modules. Representing my team in meetings within Barclays to analyze changes coming from our upstream systems.
- Part of a migration effort to expose SOAP web services to be consumed by UI.
- Maintaining an intranet web app tool making changes in both back-end and front-end.

January 2013 - May 2013

VisualDNA

London, UK

Description

Psychological quizzes, attached to web sites, collecting insight info of customer's behavior.

Technologies

Java SE 6, RESTEasy, JDBI, MySql, Jmock, Yammer Metric library.

Responsibilities

Introduced transactional support for creating/modifying quizzes as well as adding metrics for monitoring critical parts of the Rest API.

May 2011 - December 2012

VELTI

Athens, Greece

Description

Mobile marketing (Large Scale Campaigns Department).

Technologies

Java SE 6, Spring (DI, AOP), Junit/EasyMock, Maven, Resful APIs, Tomcat, Hibernate, Oracle DB.

Responsibilities

- Memory caches dealing with concurrency issues.
- Service for rolling up historical data for reporting and analysis. ER model definition, Design patterns applied (Template Method pattern, Composite).
- The last 6 months I was cooperating with our messaging team for implementing and testing HTTP APIs with our clients (mobile operators). Basic understanding of ActiveMQ.

November 2010 - February 2011 (internship) British Telecom

UK

Description Research center - British Telecommunication plc (BT), Adastral park.

Technologies-Responsibilities Installation of Hadoop on 8 slices running Ubuntu 10.04. Installing HDFS file system as well as developing Java application, leveraging the M/R API, for doing aggregations against synthetic data

constitutes of phone calls taken place between BT's subscribers.

November 2009 - August 2010

Hellenic Army

Greece

Description Served military duty to the <u>Hellenic Army</u>. Military service is a 9 month duty and it is mandatory in

Greece.

October 2008 – April 2009

ARLES INRIA

France

Description INRIA (Institut National de Recherche en Informatique et en Automatique).

Technologies-Responsibilities Java SE for assisting the development of research projects carried out at that time by the group. I worked towards our second improved version of our publication <u>Schedule-Aware Transactions for Ambient Intelligence Environments</u>.

EDUCATION

September 2005 - April 2008

University of Ioannina

Ioannina, Greece

Graduate Student

MSc., Computer Science, specialization in Software

- Graduated 8.85/10
- MSc. Thesis Title: "Content-based Searching on Unstructured P2P Systems"

Advisor: Assistant Professor Apostolos Zarras (zarras@cs.uoi.gr)

September 2000 – September 2005

University of Ioannina

Ioannina, Greece

Undergraduate Student

BSc., Computer Science

- Graduated 7.09/10
- BSc. Thesis Title: "Reliable Transactions in Ad hoc Environments"

Advisor: Assistant Professor Apostolos Zarras (zarras@cs.uoi.gr)

TRAININGS

Delivering Agile Projects with Scrums by ESI 2014.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

University of Ioannina

Ioannina, Greece

Teaching Fellow

FALL 2007: CS 4-35 – Object Oriented Programming.

FALL 2006: CS 4-35 – Object Oriented Programming.

FALL 2005: CS 4-35 – Object Oriented Programming.

The course was separated into C++ (75%) and basic Java (25%) syllabus. I was responsible for giving supporting lectures as well as correcting C++ programming assignments.

PUBLICATIONS

Conferences

V. Fotopoulos, A. Zarras, P. Vassiliadis. User-Centric Transactions for Ambient Intelligence Environments. 1st International Workshop on Ad hoc Ambient Computing (<u>AdhocAmC 2008</u>), 13 September 2008, Sophia Antipolis, France (in conjunction with 7th International Conference on AD-HOC Networks & Wireless (ADHOC-NOW)).

Journals

V. Fotopoulos, A. V. Zarras and P. Vassiliadis. <u>Schedule-Aware Transactions for Ambient Intelligence Environments</u>. International Journal of Ambient Computing and Intelligence, vol. 2, no. 4, pp. 71-86, 2010, IGI.

TECHNICAL BOOKS

Co-Author of the book "Computer Science II, Computer's Basic Principles of Information Society", V. Fotopoulos and P. Ballhs, Livanis educational publishing, 2008.

Co-Author and supervisor of the book "Computer Science V, Multimedia-Web Publishing", V. Fotopoulos, G. Nikolopoulos, K. Nikolopoulos and S. Falierhs, Livanis educational publishing, 2008.

The whole project took place in December 2005-June 2007 and has been undertaken by Greek publisher A. A. Livanis on behalf of Institute of Adult Continuing Education of the General Secretariat for Adult Education which belongs to the Ministry of National Education and Religious Affairs, Greece. The books will be used for adult education programs held by the Ministry of National Education and Religious Affairs in cooperation with municipalities of all cities of Greece.

HONORS, AWARDS

<u>IGI Global's</u> 'Fourth Annual Excellence in Research Journal Awards for 2010'. Our journal titled "Schedule-Aware Transactions for Ambient Intelligence Environments" published in International journal of Ambient Computing and Intelligence (IJACI) was chosen as the Best Published Journal Article in IJACI for 2010. IJACI is a quartered journal and our paper received the first prize for the year of 2010. According to IGI Global, the selection was based on the following criteria:

- > Contribution to the field
- > Originality of the research
- > Practicality of research results
- Quality of writing
- Rigor of the research
- > Substantive research and methodology

Hellenic Mathematical Society (H.M.S), Thalis Award, 1996-1997. Thalis is the first round of three pane-Hellenic mathematical competitions for pre-collegiate students in Greece. Creating the Greek national

team for the participation to the International Mathematical Olympiad.

LANGUAGES

- English (fluent): Lower in English (University of Michigan, USA).
- French (elementary): Attended courses in High School.
- Greek (native).

INTERESTS

I enjoy going to the gym to keep my body fit, playing basketball, cooking and socializing with my family and friends.